<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../xsl/webLog.xsl"?>
<log title="Ideas weblog" xml:lang="en">
  <topics>
    <topic created="2005-11-16" id="JsLog">
      <title>Logging</title>
      <p>Create a client-side javascript logging library, somewhat like <a href="http://alistapart.com/articles/jslogging">this one</a>, but I'm missing:</p>
      <ul>
        <li><del>Listeners: I want to connect to Mozilla's <a href="http://kb.mozillazine.org/JavaScript_Console">JavaScript Console</a>, <a href="http://developer.apple.com/internet/safari/faq.html#anchor14">Safari's counterpart</a> or even to a server (for example via <a href="http://json-rpc.org/">JSON-RPC</a>).</del> I changed my mind: not because you can, you have to do this. What would be the advantage of this anyways...</li>
        <li>Variabel inspection: this one is really important, otherwise you'll end up writing <code>info("Node #"+i+"'s class is:"+nodes[i].getClass());</code> instead of <code>info("Node #"+i+"'s class is:"+nodes[i].getClass());</code>. See my <a href="../dzLib/var-inspect.html">work in progress</a>.</li>
        <li>It has to work seamlessly: default nothing is shown; when pressing the hotkey (ctrl+\) the console is shown (it should get inserted by the code). When shown, it needs an collapse/expand behaviour: when collapsed, a small block-element handler should stay visible (just like the show/hide thing in wiki's). This behaviour must be persisted by cookies.</li>
        <li>The filter-mechanism of fvlogger should be altered to match the FireFox javascript console behaviour: when pressing <code>warn</code>, also <code>error</code> and <code>fatal</code> entries need to be displayed (logging-levels). Also: there's no need for a <code>debug</code> entry. Further: the [erase] link needs to be distinguished from the filter-actions.</li>
      </ul>
    </topic>
    <topic created="2005-11-01" id="FireFoxJavascriptConsoleIECSSDeclarations">
      <title>FireFox: mark IE CSS declarations in Javascript-console</title>
      <p>Create an <a href="http://developer.mozilla.org/en/docs/Building_an_Extension">extension</a> to mark dropped CSS declarations in the Javascript-console as IE-extensions. This would benefit FireFox as an development "platform".</p>
    </topic>
    <topic created="2005-10-26" id="HtmlFormFlashPersistence">
      <title>Client-side persistence via Flash</title>
      <p>Investigate if it's possible to persist client-side (HTML) form data in Flash. I got this idea because in the settings of the Flash player it's possible to adjust the size some local storage. After some documentation browsing I discovered persisting data in Flash is done by creating (getting) an object which seems to be persisted automatically. The code is <code>SharedObject.GetLocal("name")</code>.</p>
      <p>The thing to do now is create a movie (without UI) that communicates with HTML to persist the form-data by means of the <code>onchange</code> event of the form/controls or <code>setInterval</code>.</p>
    </topic>
    <topic created="2005-10-22" id="GmailPlusISync">
      <title>gmail iSync plugin</title>
      <p>
        It would be really nice if my address book on my Mac got synchronized with
        my GMail address book. It shouldn't be that difficult. I found some documentation.
        There is some kind of <a href="http://johnvey.com/features/gmailapi/">GMail API</a>,
        although it only retrieves address book entries at the moment. And at Apple is seems
        you can do something with iSync with their <a href="http://developer.apple.com/documentation/Cocoa/Conceptual/SyncServices/index.html">Sync Services</a>.
      </p>
      <p>
        Anyways, I probably won't find time to implement this. If you do, please notify me. And while we're busy, also look into <a href="http://mozbackup.jasnapaka.com/index.html">MozBackup</a> to backup Mozilla related data with iSync.
      </p>
    </topic>
    <topic created="2005-10-22" id="WikiFlowCharts">
      <title>Wiki Flow Charts</title>
      <p>
        Another application the world is waiting for ;-) is flow charting for Wiki's.
        I think the usage of flow charts would enrich Wiki's enormously. Basically, a flow chart
        consists of shapes (rectangles, circles) with text, connected by lines. Imagine the
        following "markup":
      </p>
      <code>[shapes]
usr:User:elipse:style(left:20px;top:20px)
web:Web server:rectangle:style(left:20px;top:120px)
db:Database:circle:style(left:20px;top:220px)

[lines]
usr:web:style(end-arrow:normal)
web:db:style(end-arrow:normal)</code>
      <p>It wouldn't be that difficult to convert this to graphics, for example with <a href="http://www.mozilla.org/projects/svg/">SVG</a> (or VML if you must), 
      or even draw it on <a href="http://weblogs.mozillazine.org/hyatt/archives/2004_07.html#005913">the canvas</a>.</p>
      <p>Of course, before it's real usable to normal people, a lot of work has to be done. Maybe a wysiwyg editor needs to be made, but I just couldn't believe nothing exists yet. I might implement something...</p>
      <p>Resources: <a href="http://developer.mozilla.org/en/docs/SVG_In_HTML_Introduction">SVG in HTML introduction</a>.
      </p>
      <p>I found <a href="http://wiki.splitbrain.org/wiki:tips:svg_support">a hint</a> of somebody wanting flow chars in their wiki's.</p>
    </topic>
		<topic created="2003-08-07" id="RegEXP_NET" comments="closed">
			<title>RegExp.NET</title>
			<p>
				One of the problems with regular expressions is that it's cryptic. 
				Another problem is (at least in javascript) you can't have sub-expressions. The 
				idea is to use one token per line, and use words for them and use 
				comments. This is actually not new, I've seen this somewhere (please 
				email me the URL if you know it). 
			</p>
			<p>
				The actual idea is to integrate this 
				with the .NET framework; create a regular expression language and a 
				compiler. This code can for simplicity be compiled to C# and .NET 
				framework regular expressions.			
			</p>
		</topic>
		<topic created="2003-08-07" id="xPath_JS">
			<title>XPath.js</title>
			<p>
				XPath implementation in javascript, so the MS selectNodes method of the 
				DOMDocument class can be used on HTML documents as well (and 
				cross-browser idem dito).
			</p>
		</topic>
		<topic created="2003-03-18">
			<title>Deploy tool</title>
			<p>
				A tool for copying the development website to a test-server or whatever server,
				only copying the changed files, according to the configuration for that
				server, copy using either SMB (network), FTP or WebDAV (HTTP), let javascript files
				be processed with an <a href="http://www.saltstorm.net/depo/esc/">cruncher</a>,
				configuration-files be configured, all determined by a deploy-file.
			</p>
			<p>
				Yes, that would be very nice (I personally <b>always</b> forget somehow to
				upload some files...).
			</p>
		</topic>
		<topic created="2003-03-16">
			<title>IIS and Rendezvous</title>
			<p>
				Wouldn't it be great to have an option to advertise webserver and 
				virtual directories through 
				<a href="http://developer.apple.com/macosx/rendezvous/index.html">Rendezvous</a>.
				For virtual directories, the Application Name could be used as Rendezvous-name.
			</p>
		</topic>
		<topic created="2003-03-16">
			<title>About this web-log</title>
			<p>	
				This web-log is meant for keeping track of my ideas. Because I have so many ideas,
				I can't implement them all. I now try to organize them, and keep prioritizing them.
				This log still needs mechanisms like last-updated, categories and some others, but this
				will do for now.
			</p>
		</topic>
  </topics>
</log>